A Register of the Albert J. and Roberta Wohlstetter Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Speeches and Writings, 1936-1996. (Box 62)
  - Notes by Albert Wohlstetter., See also Speeches and Writings/Writings
    - "White House Backgrounder on 'No Fly: Southern Iraq,' 26 August 1992,", 1992 September 1 (Folder 121: 12)
    - "New Iraqi Ground Attacks on Shiites Defy Coalition Warnings,", 1992 October 5 (Folder 121: 13)
    - "Cleaning Up After Three Campaigns,", 1992 November 16 (Folder 121: 14)
    - "Notes for Grant Reports,", 1992 December 7 (Folder 121: 15)
    - "Baltic Bias vs. Russians?", 1992 December 22 (Folder 121: 16)
    - "Discriminating Force to Stop Human Disasters,", 1992 December 31 (Folder 121: 17)
    - "Many Catastrophies, Finite Resources,", 1992 December 31 (Folder 121: 18)
    - "Rowen vs. Kravis and Lipsey?", 1993 January 6 (Folder 121: 19)
    - "Note Possibly to Be Included in Letter to Quine and in Quantum.n92,", 1993 February 12 (Folder 121: 20)
    - "Saddam's Valentine to Clinton,", 1993 February 15 (Folder 121: 21)
    - "Milosevic, Jacobin Terror and the Odd Failure of Today's Heirs of Edmund Burke,", 1993 March 28 (Folder 121: 22)
    - "Who Will Enforce a Future Division of Bosnia if the Muslims Aren't Allowed to Defend Themselves,", 1993 April 29 (Folder 121: 23)
    - "Keeping Ukraine and Bosnia Defenseless,", 1993 May 14 (Folder 121: 24)
    - "Helping the Bosnians Defend Themselves,", 1993 May 20. (Folder 121: 25)
      Includes a revised version, 1993 May 24
    - "Making Peace and Keeping It,", 1993 July 13.; See Newspaper articles
    - "EC and UN Invitation to Serbia and Croatia to Cut Up Bosnia,", 1993 October 8 (Folder 121: 26)
    - "Some Current Facts on the FSRs,", 1994 January 10 (Folder 121: 27)
    - "Carving up Bosnia Now, and Carving up the Ottoman Empire after World War I,", 1994 January 16 (Folder 121: 28)
    - "Who Will Defend Bosnia, if It Yields?", 1994 February 19 (Folder 121: 29)
    - "Russian 'Peacekeepers' Preempt NATO in Sarajevo — with an Addendum on Bill Saffire's and Tony Lewis's Shrewd Columns in the NYT Today,", 1994 February 21 (Folder 121: 30)
    - "Note for Use in the Omnilat Section in Part II Showing the Instability Implicit in Milosevic's Program for a Greater Serbia and Implicit also in Various UN and EC Plans to Divide Bosnia on the Basis of 'Ethnic Dominance',", 1994 March-April. (Folder 121: 31)
      Includes notes for revising Part I of Omnilat2.394 for Yalcin
    - "Ambiguous US and UN Warnings at Gorazde,", 1994 April 11 (Folder 121: 32)
    - "What Part Two Will Deal With,", 1993 April 14 (Folder 121: 33)
    - "Open Covenants Secretly Arrived at and Patently Incompatible,", 1994 April 22 (Folder 121: 34)
    - "For Lt. Gen. Rose and Akashi, the Serbs almost Complying Is Enough,", 1994 April 27 (Folder 121: 35)
    - "Gyrations of the UN and EC position on Serbian Aggression,", 1994 April 27 (Folder 121: 36)
    - On nationalism in Asia and Africa, Elie Kedourie, 1994 April 29 (Folder 121: 37)
    - For outline for new Wall Street Journal OpEd, 1994 May 2 (Box-folder 122: 1)
    - "The Genuine Policy Alternatives in the Balkan War Today,", 1994 May 6 (Folder 122: 2)
    - For draft for new Op-Ed, 1994 May 9 (Folder 122: 3)
    - "Brcko Is Critical for Croatia As Well As Bosnia,", 1994 May 12 (Folder 122: 4)
    - "UN Jitsu: To Make Sense of UN Resolutions and US Irresolution,", 1994 May 17. (Folder 122: 5)
      Includes revised versions, 1994 June 24 and 27
    - "Draft of a 2-Phase Operation to Permit the New Bosnia-Croatian Federation to Be Capable of Defending Itself Without Further Help from the United States,", 1994 May 19 (Folder 122: 6)
    - "French and Russian Boomerang Aid to Bosnian Serbs,", 1994 May 24 (Folder 122: 7)
    - "Connection between Milosevic's Program of Ethnic Cleansing and the Various Plans Advanced by the West for Ethnic Partition,", 1994 May 25 (Folder 122: 8)
    - On excerpt from "Lessons of Yugoslavia" by Nicole Gnesotto, 1994 May 25 (Folder 122: 9)
    - "North Korea and Bosnia: US Policy on Coalitions of the Willing,", 1994 June 6 (Folder 122: 10)
    - "Decisive for Indecision Everywhere,", 1994 June 20 (Folder 122: 11)
    - "Note on East Europe as a Source of Arms for Bosnia,", 1994 June 26 (Folder 122: 12)
    - "Izetbegovic Takes the Contact Group's Partition: The Bosnian Serbs Take It or Leave It,", 1994 July 21 (Folder 122: 13)
    - "US DOD and UN against the Engagement of Islamic Countries, or Even Secular Turkey, in Mediation or Peacekeeping in the Balkan Region,", 1994 July 21 (Folder 122: 14)
    - "US Trades UN O.K. for Russian 'Peacekeepers' in Caucasus to Get UN O.K. to Invade Haiti,", 1994 July 22 (Folder 122: 15)
    - "French Do What Karadzic Says to Do: Cut Off Sarajevo,", 1994 August 1 (Folder 122: 16)
    - "Serbia and the Cleansing of Vlasenica, B-H,", 1994 August 1 (Folder 122: 17)
    - "UN and EU Bias Against Muslims in War Crimes Trials, Mediation and Peacekeeping,", 1994 August 1 (Folder 122: 18)
    - "Mira Baratta re Today's Senate Conference on the Arms Embargo against Bosnia,", 1994 August 4 (Folder 122: 19)
    - "Noel Malcolm on the Brief 'Split' Between Karadzic and Milosevic in May 1993,", 1994 August 4 (Folder 122: 20)
    - "Roy Gutman on the Posavina Corridor and Major Milovan Milutinovic,", 1994 August 4 (Folder 122: 21)
    - "Comments and Suggestions for Mira Baratta on Sen. Nunn's Proposed Substitute for Dole/Lieberman,", 1994 August 8 (Folder 122: 22)
    - "Jim Baker Differs with Clinton's Foreign Policy Mainly in Style,", 1994 August 11 (Folder 122: 23)
    - "Suggested Opening for Action Council's 'Calling Milosevic's Bluff — Remember Why Sanctions Were Imposed',", 1994 August 11 (Folder 122: 24)
    - "Overstating the Effectiveness of International Controls or Bilateral Agreements on Cruise Missiles, Ballistic Missiles, and NBC Weapons,", 1994 August 18 (Folder 122: 25)
    - "Amb. Muhamed Sacirbey on Serbia's Lifeline to Its Proxies,", 1994 August 31 (Folder 122: 26)
    - "Conference Call with General Rasim Delic and the Elder Sacirbey,", 1994 September 12 (Folder 122: 27)
    - "Milosevic's Speech at Kosovo Polje on 25 April 1987,", 1994 September 19 (Folder 122: 28)
    - "Presidencies Ruined or Made by Foreign Crises and Character,", 1994 September 19 (Folder 122: 29)
    - "Timing Coalition Attacks and the Lifting of the Arms Embargo: Note for Pierre Hassner on François Heisbourg's View that the Embargo Should not Be Lifted Unless There Is Western Military Intervention,", 1994 September 22 (Folder 122: 30)
    - On quotes from Barbara Crossette's article in the New York Times of Saturday, 24 September, 1994, entitled "U.N. Eases Curbs on Yugoslavia after Serbian Peace Concessions,", 1994 September 26 (Folder 122: 31)
    - "Free Capital Markets in Russia, the Market and Property Rights,", 1994 September 29 (Folder 122: 32)
    - "By June 1994, Zhirinovsky's 'Far Out' View that Russia's International Borders Were the Old Soviet Borders Had Become the Yeltsin/Kozyrev View—and Clinton/Albright's,", 1994 October 3 (Folder 122: 33)
    - "Slobo's Detailed Control and Calibration from Outset of JNA Massive Air and Ground Interventions Inside Croatia and Bosnia: Ante Markovic's Tape Recordings,", 1994 October 3 (Folder 122: 34)
    - "Excerpts on Russia's Parliamentary Elections of 12 Dec 93 From Vera Tolz and Elizabeth Teague in RFE/RL RR, 14 Jan 94,", 1994 October 7 (Folder 122: 35)
    - "Outline for VrtLinks.094: Irresolution Everywhere Resolving Crises by Irresolution,", 1994 October 13 (Folder 122: 36)
    - "U.S. Yields to North Korean 'Diplomacy',", 1994 October 20 (Folder 122: 37)
    - "Potential Use of Differential GPS in Bosnia to Disrupt Fuel Distribution to Serbs, Etc.,", 1994 November 4 (Folder 122: 38)
    - "Bosnian Plot to Get Slaughtered?", 1994 November 29 (Folder 122: 39)
    - "U.S. Marines to Rescue UNPROFOR?", 1994 November 29 (Folder 122: 40)
    - "Evidence that Cutting Fuel from Serbia Quickly Hurts Serbia's Proxies,", 1994 December 5 (Folder 122: 41)
    - "How Air Power Can Tip the Balance on the Ground in Bosnia,", 1994 December 5. (Folder 122: 42)
      Includes a different version entitled, "How Precise Air Power Can Tip the Balance on the Ground in Bosnia," 1994 December 5
    - "War of Aggression in Bosnia Is the Latest Clinton Backflip-Flop,", 1994 December 5 (Folder 122: 43)
    - "Widening the War: Christopher vs. Reality,", 1994 December 5 (Folder 122: 44)
    - "Serbian Orthodox Church Attacked Pope's Sarajevo Visit, Charging Catholics Killed Serbs for Hitler in World War II,", 1994 December 16 (Folder 122: 45)
    - "Losing Diplomacy vs. Winning Air Power: Colvin on Air Power to Cut Resupply to North Vietnam from China and Russia,", 1994 December 19 (Folder 122: 46)
    - On Brett Barkey's Bosnia: The Question of Intervention, 1994 December 19 (Folder 122: 47)
    - "BB-G's Impartiality,", 1995 January 2 (Folder 122: 48)
    - On North Korea, South Korea, Russia and China, 1995 January 2 (Folder 122: 49)
    - "Boris Yeltsin as Abraham Lincoln,", 1995 January 5 (Folder 122: 50)
    - "KGB Gangs Cleansing 'Gangs' in the FSRs and the Russian Republics, Including Russia Itself,", 1995 January 11 (Box-folder 123: 1)
    - "Free Markets vs. Mafia-Style Privatization,", 1995 January 12 (Folder 123: 2)
    - "How Protect the Independence of the Former Warsaw Pact Countries in East Europe?", 1995 January 17 (Folder 123: 3)
    - "Strategic Inhumane Acts: Why Humanitarian Convoys Could not Make Up for Facilitating Serbia's Genocide,", 1995 February 22 (Folder 123: 4)
    - "The UN Veto on NATO Air Strikes – Now and in 1993 – When the Serbs Closed the Ring around Sarajevo,", 1995 June 28 (Folder 123: 5)
    - "U.S. Surrealpolitik in Iraq and in Serbia: Preserving Genocidal Dictatorship for an Automatic Regional Balance: Letting the Baath Dictatorship Use Helicopter Gunships against the Shiites We Had Asked to Revolt,", 1995 August 23 (Folder 123: 6)
    - "NATO: Precise Power, Incoherent Goals,", 1995 October 11 (Folder 123: 7)
    - "Rebuilding the Threats: From Helsinki and Back,", 1995 October 13 (Folder 123: 8)
    - "Magic Tricks Can't Hide This,", 1995 November 9 (Folder 123: 9)
    - "James Gow Linked Gulf War's End and Balkan War's Start,", 1995 December 30 (Folder 123: 10)
    - "Hiding and Rewarding Genocide: Lord Owen's--and the West's--Balkan Odyssey" (with Roberta Wohlstetter), 1996 February 4 (Folder 123: 11)
    - "Dole, the Beltway and the World Outside," revised, 1996 May 3 (Folder 123: 12)
    - "Notes: Photos Belying the Photo-Ops,", 1996 July 19. (Folder 123: 13)
  - Research materials., See also Roberta Wohlstetter File
    Includes clippings and printed matter, conversations, correspondence, memoranda, notes, remarks, reports, writings by others, and telegrams.
    - General (Folder 123: 14)
    - Arms race (Folder 123: 15)
    - Cuba. These materials may have been used by either or both Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter for their writings on Cuba (Folder 123: 16-20)
    - Cuba (Box-folder 124: 1-7)
    - India (Folder 124: 8-11)
    - India (Box 125 -128)
    - Persian Gulf (Box-folder 129: 1-4)
    - Ukraine and other former Soviet republics (Folder 129: 5)
    - Vietnam (Folder 129: 6)
  - Speeches., See also background materials
    Includes comments, lectures, remarks, and talks, as well as conversations.
    - General (Folder 129: 7)
    - C3 lectures, n.d. (Folder 129: 8)
      Typescript. Includes related materials
    - "Political Economy of Peace and War," talk (Folder 129: 9)
    - "Scientists, Seers and Strategy," talk, Columbia University, New York (Folder 129: 10)
    - "Tech Trends Make Feasible Operations," remarks, Hawaii (Folder 129: 11)
    - "Turkey and the Defense of Western Interests," speech
      - Background materials (Folder 129: 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 129: 13)
    - Speech on employment, and labor reserve in time of war, and the measurement of these phenomena, National Bureau of Economic Research, 1942 August 10. (Folder 129: 14)
    - Talk, 1942 December 2
      - Background materials (Folder 129: 15)
      - Notes (Folder 129: 16)
      - Outline (Folder 129: 17)
    - Lecture, Harvard University, Massachusetts, 1947 April 24. (Folder 129: 18)
      Outline and typescript
    - "End Run," talk, 1956? (Box 130)
      - Background materials (Folder 130: 1)
      - Outline (Folder 130: 2)
    - Conversation, Strategic Deterrence, Military Assistance Group (MAG), 1957 November 20
      - Notes (Folder 130: 3)
      - Typescript (Folder 130: 4)
    - "Deterrence after 1960: Overseas Bases and the Alliance," talk, Council on Foreign Relations, 1958 May 26
    - Outline (Folder 130: 5)
    - Typescript (Folder 130: 6-7)
    - "Delicate Balance of Terror," speech, World Affairs Council, California, 1958 September 25. (Folder 130: 8)
    - "Balance of Missile Gap," speech, Harvard University, Massachusetts, 1959 February 11
      - Background materials (Folder 130: 9)
      - Correspondence (Folder 130: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 130: 11)
    - Lecture, Soviet Strategy, National Defense College, Ottawa, Canada, 1959 February 26. (Folder 130: 12)
    - "Deterrence in the 1960's," talk, Council on Foreign Relations, 1959 March 30. (Folder 130: 13)
    - Talk, Phi Beta Kappa, Westport, Connecticut, 1959 June 4. (Folder 130: 14)
    - "What Can Be Done in the Early Sixties," talk, SOFS I, II, and III, 1959 August 24. (Folder 130: 15)
    - Talk on defense, Fort Ritchie, Maryland, 1959 September. (Folder 130: 16)
    - "Objectives of U.S. Military Posture,", 1960 February 28
      - Notes (Folder 130: 17)
      - Outline (Folder 130: 18)
    - "Test Ban as a Measure of Serious Attitudes on Arms Control," talk, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California, 1960 August 2 (Box 131)
      - Background materials (Folder 131: 1)
      - Notes (Folder 131: 2)
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 131: 3-4)
    - Discussion comments, Western Values and Total War, Commentary, 1961 October. (Folder 131: 5)
    - Conversation with Luigi Einaudi, 1961 November 2. (Folder 131: 6)
      Notes (with Roberta Wohlstetter)
    - Talk, Mount St. Mary's, 1962 March 5. (Folder 131: 7)
    - Conversation with Wilhelm von Cornides on German contribution to the study of arms policy and stability in Europe, Bad Godesberg, Germany, 1962 July 2. (Folder 131: 8)
    - Comments on Theodore Draper's talk, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California, 1962 September. (Folder 131: 9)
    - Conversation with Arnold Kramish on first Russian shot, 1963 March 7. (Folder 131: 10)
      Typewritten summary
    - "Technology, Prediction and Disorder," speech, Science and Technology, session I, Forces of Change, Stability and Change Through Law, School of Law, Vanderbilt University Law Review, Vanderbilt University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1963 April 4-6
      - General (Folder 131: 11)
      - Background materials (Folder 131: 12)
      - Notes and typescript (Folder 131: 13)
    - Talk, Endicott House, 1963 June 4. (Folder 131: 14)
    - "Automatic Stability of Peace and Inevitability of War," talk, Bonn, Germany, 1963 August 28. (Folder 131: 15)
    - "Experts and Amateurs in a Democracy," talk, San Demas, California, 1963 November. (Box-folder 132: 1)
      Notes and outline
    - "Who Speaks for Peace?" comments, Bay Area Program on KQED, San Francisco, California, 1964 February
      - General. (Folder 132: 2)
        Includes a letter from Caspar Weinberger, 1964 February 14
      - Review (Folder 132: 3)
    - "Sin and Games," speech, University of California, Berkeley, California, 1964 February 13
      - Background materials (Folder 132: 4)
      - Correspondence (Folder 132: 5)
      - Notes (Folder 132: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 132: 7-10)
      - Galley (Folder 132: 11)
      - Printed copy (Folder 132: 12)
      - Review (Folder 132: 13)
    - "War by Mistake," lecture, University of Oregon, Oregon, 1964 November 5-6. (Box-folder 133: 1)
    - "On the Strategic Balance and Its Political Implication," talk, Ivrea, Italy, 1965. (Folder 133: 2)
      - Outline
    - Conversation with Dennis Healey, 1965
      - Correspondence (Folder 133: 3)
      - Notes (Folder 133: 4)
    - Talk, Ditchley, Oxfordshire, England, 1965 May 1. (Folder 133: 5)
    - Lecture on relations among the nuclear and non-nuclear powers, Political Science Association, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, 1965 November 22
      - Notes (Folder 133: 6)
      - Typescript (Folder 133: 7)
    - Conversation with chiefs of OR in three services – air force, army, and navy, Tokyo, Japan, 1966 Spring
      - General (Folder 133: 8)
      - Background materials? (Folder 133: 9)
      - Typewritten summary (Folder 133: 10)
    - "Costs and Effects of Small Nuclear Forces," speech, Sapru House, New Delhi, India, 1966 April 18. (Folder 133: 11)
    - Talk, U.S. Embassy, New Delhi, India, 1966 April 21. (Folder 133: 12)
    - Lectures, National Defense College, Ottawa, Canada, 1966 May 1 and 3. (Box-folder 134: 1)
    - Talk on crisis studies, Tel Aviv, Israel, 1966 April 28 and Jerusalem, 1966 May 3
      - Background materials (Folder 134: 2)
      - Notes (Folder 134: 3)
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 134: 4)
    - "The Nuclear Future of Asia and the Middle East," talk, Rome, 1966 May 5. (Folder 134: 5)
    - "Atoms for Equality?" speech, Council on Religion and International Affairs, 1967 January 9. (Folder 134: 6)
    - Lecture on Robert McNamara's posture statement, Washington, D.C., 1967 February 15
      - General (Folder 134: 7)
      - Background materials (Folder 134: 8)
      - Correspondence. Albert Wohlstetter's letter to Robert McNamara (Folder 134: 9)
      - Notes (Folder 134: 10)
      - Typescript (Folder 134: 11)
      - Review (Folder 134: 12)
    - Conversation with Joint War Games Agency on issues in a senior-level politico-military game, Pentagon, Washington, D.C., 1967 April 25-May 16
      - General (Folder 134: 13)
      - Correspondence. Letter of invitation to Albert Wohlstetter from Earle G. Wheeler (Folder 134: 14)
      - Notes (Folder 134: 15)
    - "Experts and Amateurs in a Democracy," speech, 1967 October 17
      - Notes (Folder 134: 16)
      - Outline (Folder 134: 17)
    - Talk, Fermi celebration on the peaceful atom, 1967 November 28. (Folder 134: 18)
    - "A Perspective on Nuclear Energy," lecture, 25th anniversary observance of the first-controlled self-sustaining nuclear reaction, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, 1967 December 5
      - Typescript (Folder 134: 19)
      - Responses (Folder 134: 20)
    - "The Experts and the Cardinal Choices," talk, 1967 December 13. (Folder 134: 21)
    - Conversation with David Packard, Wieser, Weiss, etc., 1969 October-November. (Folder 134: 22)
    - Telephone conversation with Sy Weiss, 1970 January-November. (Folder 134: 23)
    - Talk, GAC-ACDA, 1970 February 27. (Folder 134: 24)
    - Comments to Henry Kissinger, Strategic Arms Limitation Talks (SALT), 1970 July 30. (Folder 134: 25)
    - Conversation with KWS and Henry Kissinger, 1971 January. (Folder 134: 26)
    - Lecture, All Souls College, Oxford, England, 1971 May 12
      - Background materials (Folder 134: 27)
      - Notes (Folder 134: 28)
      - Outline and typescript (Folder 134: 29)
    - Talk, Japan, 1972 May 31. (Folder 134: 30)
    - "SALT Agreements: Comparative Advantages," talk, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California, 1972 June 9. (Folder 134: 31)
    - Conversation with McCutcheon, ORI, 1972 August 1. (Folder 134: 32)
    - Conversation with Elliot Richardson, 1973 January. (Folder 134: 33)
    - Conversation with Isaac Schapiro, Japan Study Group, California Seminar, New York City, 1973 March 6, and Albert and Roberta Wohlstetter's conversation with Saeki, Chicago, 1973 April 14. (Folder 134: 34)
    - Arthur Steiner lecture, 1973 November 12. (Folder 134: 35)
    - Conversation with Edward Teller, 1974 July 25. (Box-folder 135: 1)
    - "Future Options and Technologies of Discrimination," talk, Ebenhausen, Germany, 1974 October 12. (Folder 135: 2)
    - Telephone conversation with Phil Lantz and Dave Mc Garvey, 1974 December 11
      - Background materials (Folder 135: 3)
      - Correspondence (Folder 135: 4)
      - Typewritten summary (Folder 135: 5)
    - Introductory lecture on the state of strategic policy in the USA with special consideration of developments made in the technology of arms, Study Group for International Security, German Society for Foreign Policy, Bonn, Germany, 1975 March 26. (Folder 135: 6)
      Typewritten summary and transcripts in German and English
    - "Spread of Nuclear Technology," talk, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California, 1975 November 5
      - Background materials (Folder 135: 7)
      - Notes (Folder 135: 8)
      - Outline (Folder 135: 9)
    - "Spread of Nuclear Technology," talk, Chicago, Illinois, 1975 November 18
      - Correspondence (Folder 135: 10)
      - Outline (Folder 135: 11)
    - Conversation with Andy Marshall on intelligence problem, 1975 December 19. (Folder 135: 12)
    - Conversation with Donald Rumsfeld, 1976 December. (Folder 135: 13)
    - Talk on non-proliferation, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C., 1976 December. (Folder 135: 14)
    - Talk, ACDA, 1977 February. (Folder 135: 15)
    - Telephone conversation with Dick Spier, 1977 February 4. (Folder 135: 16)
    - "Key Points on Non Proliferation Policy," conversation with Henry Rowen, 1977 March 14. (Folder 135: 17)
    - Talk on casual observations on neutron or cartron bomb, 1978 April 21
      - General (Folder 135: 18)
      - Background materials (Folder 135: 19)
      - Notes (Folder 135: 20)
    - Remarks on miscellaneous subjects during a visit to Argonne National Laboratory, Chicago, Illinois, 1978 May 25-26
      - Background materials (Folder 135: 21)
      - Typewritten summary of remarks by Albert Wohlstetter, Henry Rowen, Gregory Jones, and Brian G. Chow, prepared by Brian Chow and Gregory Jones, 1978 June 13 (Folder 135: 22)
    - Comments on SALT Treaty II, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, 1979 May 24
      - Background materials (Folder 135: 23)
      - Typewritten transcript. (Folder 135: 24)
        Includes a revised version, 1979 August 3
    - Remarks, question and answer session on SALT, University of Chicago, Chicago, Illinois, 1979 August 2. (Folder 135: 25)
    - Talk on security analysts, Chicago, Illinois, 1979 November 1
      - Background materials (Folder 135: 26)
      - Outline (Folder 135: 27)
    - Talk, Georgetown University, Washington, D.C., 1980. (Folder 135: 28)
    - Talk on defense expansion, Hoover Institution, Stanford University, California, 1980 February 26. (Folder 135: 29)
    - Remarks, Sanford S. Parker Memorial Service, University Chapel, Columbia University, New York, 1980 March 5. (Folder 135: 30)
    - Talk, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena, California, 1981 April 13. (Folder 135: 31)
    - "Problem of Protecting U.S. Interests," Hoover Institution, Stanford University, California, 1981 May. (Folder 135: 32)
    - "Political, Economic, and Military Strategy for Competing with the Soviet Bloc," talk, Okinawa, Japan, 1982 May 21. (Folder 135: 33-34)
    - "Pacific Strategy in a 1980's Global Setting," talk, Monterey, California, 1982 June 10-11 (Box 136)
      - Background materials (Folder 136: 1)
      - Notes (Folder 136: 2)
      - Typescript (Folder 136: 3)
    - Comments on Wörner/Wurzbach study of conventional force modernization and on Senator Sam Nunn's report on NATO, entitled "Can the Alliance Be Saved,", 1982 June 26. (Folder 136: 4)
    - Conversation with General Aharon Yariv (with Roberta Wohlstetter, Richard Brody, Greg Jones, and Shai Feldman), Century Plaza, New York, 1982 July 2. (Folder 136: 5)